Guide to the Asian Women's Institute - North American Office Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Conferences and Consultations, Series IV
  - Tenth Anniversary celebrations - Hong Kong (originally to be held in New Delhi): arrangements, planning, 1985 Jan (Box 22, Folder 200)
  - Tenth Anniversary celebrations - Hong Kong: arrangements, planning, 1985 Jan (Box 22, Folder 201-203)
  - Educational Conference: "The New Asian Woman in the 21st Century" - Hong Kong, 1985 Jan 21-24 (Box 22, Folder 204)
  - Triennial Conference of the Presidents' Consultation of the Consortium Colleges in Asia- Hong Kong, 1985 Jan 25-28 (Box 22, Folder 205)
  - Triennial conference: "Together for Justice Through Education and Development" - Indonesia: programme, reports, 1988 Jun 28-30 (Box 22, Folder 206)
  - Triennial conference - Indonesia: arrangements, 1987-1988 (Box 23, Folder 207)
  - Triennial Conference of the Presidents' Consultation - Indonesia, 1988 Jul 1-4 (Box 23, Folder 208)
  - Directors' Workparty - Indonesia, 1988 Jul 1- 4 (Box 23, Folder 209)
  - First Margaret Flory Forum - "Women and the Environment in an Age of Technology - Perspectives from the Two-Thirds World" - NY, 1990 Mar 8 (Box 23, Folder 210)
  - Triennial conference: "Women and Environment in an Age of Technology" - Kobe College, Japan: programme, report, 1991Sep 24- Oct 7 (Box 23, Folder 211)
  - Triennial conference: "Women and Environment in an Age of Technology" - Kobe College, Japan: arrangements, planning, 1988-1991 (Box 23, Folder 212)
  - Triennial Conference of the Presidents' Consultation - Kobe College, Japan, 1991 Oct 3-5 (Box 23, Folder 213)
- Programs and Projects, Series V
  - Travel Seminars
    - Japan and Korea travel seminar, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 214)
    - Japan and Korea travel seminar, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 215)
  - Leadership Development Programme
    - Description of project, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 216)
    - Corres. re. funding and arrangements, 1985-1991 (Box 24, Folder 217-219)
    - Info. re. student exchangees, 1985-1986 (Box 24, Folder 220)
    - Letters/ reports from students exchangees, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 221)
  - Commission on Women and Work
    - Reports, 1978-1988 (Box 24, Folder 222)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 25, Folder 223)
    - Aspirations - career planning handbook for Asian women; Career Counseling; Women and Work in Asia, 1983, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 224)
  - AWI Peacemaking Team
    - Planning material, corres., 1982-1984 (Box 25, Folder 225-226)
    - Reports, 1983-1985 (Box 25, Folder 227-228)
  - Cluster program
    - Planning materials, corres., 1982-1985 (Box 26, Folder 229-231)
    - Albany/ Schenectady Cluster, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 232)
    - Atlanta Cluster, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 233)
    - Baltimore Cluster, 1982-1984 (Box 26, Folder 234)
    - Boston Cluster, 1982-1983 (Box 26, Folder 235)
    - Chicago Cluster, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 236)
    - Claremont Cluster, 1982-1990 (Box 26, Folder 237-239)
    - Columbus Cluster, 1984-1985 (Box 26, Folder 240)
    - Mountain Grove Cluster, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 241)
    - Nashville Cluster, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 242)
    - Northern New Jersey Cluster, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 243)
    - Pacific Northwest Cluster, 1982-1984 (Box 27, Folder 244)
    - Pittsburgh Cluster, 1984-1990 (Box 27, Folder 245-246)
    - St. Louis/ Topeka Cluster, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 247)
    - St. Petersburg Beach Cluster, 1982-1984 (Box 27, Folder 248)
    - Stony Point Cluster, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 249)
    - Washington Cluster, 1982-1984 (Box 27, Folder 250)
    - Toronto Cluster, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 251)
    - Vancouver Cluster, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 252)
  - Other programs and events
    - AWI Tenth Anniversary events/ programs in NYC, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 254)
    - AWI Research Projects, 1980-1984 (Box 27, Folder 255)
    - Faculty Exchange Program, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 256)
    - Tree Planting Project, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 257)
- Colleges and Centers in Asia, Series VI
  - General
    - Reports of joint research projects, 1979-1980 (Box 28, Folder 258)
  - India
    - Hawabagh Women's College, Jabalpur
      - Reports of Women's Centre, 1983-1987 (Box 28, Folder 259)
      - Publications, papers, 1983-1988 (Box 28, Folder 260)
      - Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 28, Folder 261)
    - Isabella Thoburn College, Lucknow
      - Reports of Women's Centre, 1975-1988 (Box 28, Folder 262)
      - "Newzlink" of Centre for Women's Studies and Development, 1977-1981 (Box 28, Folder 263-264)
      - Papers, proposals re. research, 1978-1980 (Box 28, Folder 265)
      - Publications re. Isabella Thoburn College in general, 1970-1983 (Box 29, Folder 266)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1989 (Box 29, Folder 267-269)
    - St. Christopher's College of Education, Madras
      - Reports of Womens' Study Centre, 1977-1989 (Box 29, Folder 270)
      - Publications, photos, etc. re. St. Christopher's College in general, 1967-1980, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 271-272)
      - Correspondence, 1968-1988 (Box 30, Folder 273-274)
    - Women's Christian College, Madras
      - Reports of Madras Women's Centre, 1978-1989 (Box 30, Folder 275)
      - Project proposal on "The Role of Urban Women in National Development", 1977 (Box 30, Folder 276)
      - Material re. Women's Christian College as a whole: Board and Council minutes and reports, 1968-1984 (Box 30, Folder 277)
      - Material re. Women's Christian College as a whole: Publications, brochures, 1960-1978, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 278)
      - Material re. Women's Christian College as a whole: Photographs, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 279a)
      - Correspondence, 1969-1987 (Box 30, Folder 279b-280)
  - Iran
    - Damavand College, Tehran
      - Publications, reports re. Women's Institute, 1977-1978, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 281)
      - Publications, constitution, photographs re. Damavand College as a whole, 1976-1978 (Box 31, Folder 282)
      - Correspondence, 1972-1980 (Box 31, Folder 283)
  - Japan
    - Kobe College
      - Reports, corres. re. Institute for Women's Studies, 1985-1989 (Box 31, Folder 284)
      - Re. Kobe College as a whole, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 285)
    - Tokyo Woman's Christian University - Tokyo Joshi Daigaku
      - Reports of Center for Women's Studies; Center publication: Brief History of Higher Education for Women in Japan by E. Nagura, 1977-1981 (Box 31, Folder 286)
      - Reports of Center for Women's Studies, 1982-1989, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 287)
      - Material re. TWCU as a whole: Newsletters, brochures, photos, 1968-1984 (Box 31, Folder 288)
      - Material re. TWCU as a whole: Annual reports of President, 1971-1984 (Box 32, Folder 289)
      - Material re. TWCU as a whole: Misc. publications, events, 1973-1978 (Box 32, Folder 290)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1983 (Box 32, Folder 291)
  - Korea
    - Ewha Womans University, Seoul
      - Reports of Korean Women's Institute, 1977-1989 (Box 32, Folder 292)
      - Material re. Ewha as a whole: Ewha Voice, 1969-1976 (Box 32, Folder 293)
      - Material re. Ewha as a whole: Ewha Voice, 1977-1985 (Box 32, Folder 294)
      - Material re. Ewha as a whole: brochures, 1975-1983, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 295)
      - Material re. Ewha as a whole: photographs, photo diaries, 1973-1982, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 296)
      - Material re. Ewha as a whole: reports, articles, 1970-1985, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 297)
      - Correspondence: Ewha / AWI, 1972-1986 (Box 33, Folder 298)
      - Correspondence: International Foundation for EWHA Womans University, 1968-1975 (Box 33, Folder 299)
    - Seoul Woman's College / University
      - Reports of Women's Studies Institute, 1976-1989 (Box 33, Folder 300)
      - Material re. SWC as a whole: brochures, photos, 1977-1978, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 301)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1989 (Box 34, Folder 302-303)
  - Lebanon
    - Beirut University College (formerly Beirut College for Women)
      - Reports of Institute for Women's Studies in the Arab World, 1973-1988 (Box 34, Folder 304)
      - Institute for Women's Studies in the Arab World: brochures, misc. reports, articles, 1980-1985, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 305)
      - Institute for Women's Studies in the Arab World: Al Raida, 1977-1987 (Box 34, Folder 306)
      - Material re. BUC as a whole: brochures, photos, 1972-1985, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 307)
      - Material re. BUC as a whole: newsletters, 1972-1979, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 308)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1988 (Box 35, Folder 309)
  - Pakistan
    - Kinnaird College for Women, Lahore
      - Reports of Pakistan Women's Institute, 1980-1989 (Box 35, Folder 310)
      - Pakistan Women's Institute Newsletter, 1976-1988 (Box 35, Folder 311-312)
      - PWI research proposals, surveys, reports - Career Counselling, ca. 1980 (Box 35, Folder 313)
      - PWI program material, 1978, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 314)
      - Material re. Kinnaird College as a whole, 1967-1984 (Box 36, Folder 315)
      - Correspondence, 1972--1989 (Box 36, Folder 316-319)
      - Biographical information on Mira Phailbus, 1975-1980 (Box 36, Folder 320)
  - Philippines
    - Silliman University, Damaguete City
      - Reports of Center for Women Studies and Development, 1982-1989 (Box 36, Folder 321)
      - CWSD program material, publications, 1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 322)
    - Harris Memorial College, Manila
      - Reports, brochures re. Development Center for Women, Inc., 1974, 1987, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 323)
    - Northern Christian College, Laoag City
      - Report, corres. re Centre for Women's Studies, 1983-1989 (Box 37, Folder 324)
    - Philippines Cluster
      - Reports, 1983, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 325)
      - Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 37, Folder 326)
- Publications and Promotional Material, Series VII
  - Periodical publications
    - Asian Women's Institute Newsletter
      - issues, 1975-1977 (Box 37, Folder 327)
    - Asian Woman
      - issues, 1977-1993 (Box 37, Folder 328-332)
      - mailing lists, 1985, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 333)
      - mailing lists, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 334)
      - correspondence, 1977-1984 (Box 38, Folder 335-336)
      - report, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 337)
    - Committee of 75 Newsletter
      - issues and corres., 1977-1980 (Box 38, Folder 338)
  - Articles and papers
    - About the AWI, 1977-1990 (Box 38, Folder 339)
    - By AWI-related staff re. women in India, women's higher education in Asia, 1976- 1990 (Box 38, Folder 340)
  - Brochures
    - AWI/ Association brochures (Box 38, Folder 341-342)
    - AWI/ Association brochures: designs/ drafts (Box 38, Folder 343)
    - Leaflets re. AWI member colleges (Box 39, Folder 344)
    - Leaflets re. AWI member colleges: designs/ drafts (Box 39, Folder 345)
  - Appeals
    - Misc. appeal letters/ address lists (Box 39, Folder 346-350)
    - Promotional events (Box 39, Folder 351)
  - Audio-visual material and artifacts
    - re. AWI film/ slide show: "Women for Tomorrow's World", 1974-1975 n.d. (Box 39, Folder 352)
    - re. Puppet show - CWU meeting at Purdue, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 353)
    - Hand puppets - representations of international women (Indian, Japanese, etc.) (Box OV1–OV3)
    - AWI slide-tape shows:"Education for Life", "Grace Revolts", 1979 (Box 39, Folder 354)
    - Proposed slide-tape show, 1984 (Box 40, Folder 355)
    - Photographs - Triennial meeting, Tokyo, 1978 (Box 40, Folder 356)
    - Photographs - Career seminar, Singapore; Association meeting, 1979 (Box 40, Folder 357)
    - Photographs - Peace Team, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 358)
    - Photographs - misc. individuals, 1976-1978, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 359)
    - Photographs - misc. events, scenes, 1976-1988, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 360)
    - Audiocassettes - misc. events, 1975-1982, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 361)
- Membership Records, Series VIII
  - Association members and donors
    - Lists, 1971-1987, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 362-367)
  - College administrators and alumnae
    - Administrators and board members, 1971-1981, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 368)
    - Beirut University College alumnae and supporters (Box 41, Folder 369)
    - Damavand College alumnae and supporters (Box 41, Folder 370)
    - Ewha and Tokyo Woman's Christian College alumnae and supporters (Box 41, Folder 371)
- Financial Records, Series IX
  - Financial summaries
    - Proposed budgets, financial statements, etc., 1972-1977 (Box 41, Folder 372)
    - Proposed budgets, financial statements, etc., 1978-1983 (Box 41, Folder 373)
    - Sampling of operational records, 1983 Jan-Jun (Box 42, Folder 374)
    - Proposed budgets, financial statements, etc., 1984-1992 (Box 42, Folder 375-378)
  - Internal communications re. finance
    - Memos, letters, appeals, 1973-1988 (Box 42, Folder 379)
  - Communications with supporting organizations
    - American Baptist Churches, 1982-1987 (Box 42, Folder 380)
    - Church Women United, 1973-1985 (Box 42, Folder 381-382)
    - CACHEA - Commission for the Advancement of Christian Higher Education in Asia, 1973-1974 (Box 42, Folder 383)
    - CODEL - Coordination in Development, Inc., 1983-1984 (Box 42, Folder 384)
    - Fellowship of the Least Coin, 1977-1985 (Box 42, Folder 385)
    - Netherlands Reformed Church, 1983-1985 (Box 42, Folder 386)
    - Presbyterian - U.S. and U.S.A., 1976-1985 (Box 42, Folder 387)
    - United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia, 1979-1990 (Box 42, Folder 388)
    - United Methodist Church, 1976-1980 (Box 43, Folder 389)
    - Virginia Gildersleeve International Fund for University Women, 1976-1980 (Box 43, Folder 390)
    - Misc. other denominations, 1978-1988 (Box 43, Folder 391)
    - Misc. foundations and groups, 1976-1982 (Box 43, Folder 392)
- Related Organizations, 1974; Series X
  - Church Women United, 1974-1984 (Box 43, Folder 393-395)
  - National Council of Churches - Division of Overseas Ministries, 1982-1984 (Box 43, Folder 396)
  - National Council of Community Churches, 1983-1984 (Box 43, Folder 397)
  - United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia, 1981-1989 (Box 43, Folder 398)
  - United Nations, 1984-1985 (Box 43, Folder 399)
  - Wellesley College Center for Research on Women, 1975 (Box 43, Folder 400)
  - Wellesley College Center for Women's Careers, 1983-1985 (Box 43, Folder 401)
  - Misc. other organizations, 1977-1982 (Box 43, Folder 402)
- Collected Material, Series XI
  - Articles and essays
    - Misc., primarily re. women's issues (Box 44, Folder 403-404)
    - Materials issued by United Nations (Box 44, Folder 405-406)
  - Periodical issues
    - The Asian Church Woman, 1981-1987 (Box 44, Folder 407-409)
    - Issues of misc. other periodicals related to women's issues, 1977-1985 (Box 45, Folder 410)
  - Monographs, conference reports
    - Asian Women - pub. by Christian Conference of Asia, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 411)
    - Breaking Through - a Bibliography of Women and Religion - by Clare B. Fischer - Graduate Theological Union Library, Berkeley, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 412)
    - By Our Lives - Stories of women today and in the Bible - pub. by World Council of Churches, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 413)
    - Creation Sings - language inclusive song book pub. by Geneva Press, 1979 (Box 45, Folder 414)
    - The Emerging Woman - study/activity booklet by P. Palmer and J. Skolnick; Hidden from History Program, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 415)
    - The Iranian Woman - past and present - pub. by The Women's Organisation of Iran (Box 45, Folder 416)
    - Lamps are for Lighting - the story of Helen Barrett Montgomery and Lucy Waterbury Peabody - by Lousie A. Cattan; Eerdman's Pub. Co., 1972 (Box 45, Folder 417)
    - Lucknow - compiled by The American Women's Club, Lucknow, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 418)
    - A Survey of Research Concerns on Women's Issues - by Arlene Kaplan Daniels; Assn. of American Colleges, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 419)
    - Third World Women Speak Out - by Perdita Huston; Praeger Publishers, 1979 (Box 45, Folder 420)
    - Vigilant Women - Vigil India Movement, 1981 (Box 45, Folder 421)
    - The Vital Role of the University for Change - proceedings of UBCHEA workshop in Korea, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 422)
    - Voices of Women: an Asian anthology - vol II, ed. by Alison O'Grady, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 423)
    - With Babies and Banners - illustrated historical booklet pub. by Women as History: Past and Present (Box 46, Folder 424)
    - Woman to Woman - Asian women in solidarity... Christian Conference of Asia Women's Concerns, 1986 (Box 46, Folder 425)
    - Women - a bibliography 1975-1978 - pub. by American Council of Voluntary Agencies for Foreign Service, Inc. (Box 46, Folder 426)
    - Women and Development - report of Wingspread Workshop convened by Center for Research and Development, Wellesley College, in cooperation with The Johnson Foundation, 1976 (Box 46, Folder 427)
    - Women and Men in Asia - the woman question in the Asian context - WSCF Asia Book No. 5, 1978 (Box 46, Folder 428)
    - Women and Work in Lebanon - Institute for Women's Studies in the Arab World, Beirut University College, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 429)
    - Women in Asia for Justice and Development - ASISCA Women's Consultation, Kyoto, Japan, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 430)
    - Women in Turkey - by Tezer Taskiran; Redhouse Press, 1976 (Box 46, Folder 431)
    - Women: The Fifth World - by Elise Boulding; Foreign Policy Association - Headline Series 248, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 432)
    - Women working: Toward a new society - by Alan Pifer; Carnegie Corp. report, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 433)
    - Women of the Pacific and Southeast Asia - proceedings of 15th international conf. of Pan Pacific and Southeast Asia Women's Assn. - re. lifelong education and training for women, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 434)
    - "Women's Work is..." - Resources on working women - ed. by Bobbi Wells Hargleroad; Institute on the Church in Urban -Industrial Society, Chicago, 1978 (Box 46, Folder 435)
- Addendum, Series XII
  - History and overview
    - Proposals to establish Asian Women's Institute, 1972 May (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Documents, incl. Report of Findings Committee and case statement on AWI, 1974 Oct - 1975 May (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Constitution of the Association, materials re. related organization, memorial tribute, 1974 Dec-1978 Feb (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Organization / committee Records
    - Association of North American Cooperating Agencies of Overseas Women's Christian Colleges
      - Minutes of organizing meeting; annual meeting minutes, 1971 Oct - 1974 Oct (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Steering Committee minutes, 1971 Nov - 1975 Mar (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Association of Christians for Women's Education in Asia
      - Policy statement and reports, 1982-1984 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Steering Committee agenda and minutes, 1986 May-1987 Jun (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Association of Nine Colleges in Asia
      - Minutes, Coordinator's reorts, 1975 Oct - 1977 Jul (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Executive Committee minutes, 1976 Jan - 1977 Jul (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Committee of 75
      - Reports, minutes, memoranda, 1976-1986 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Asian Women's Institute
      - Executive Committee agenda; Steering Committee minutes, 1976 Jul - 1985 Oct (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - Financial records; proposed budget, 1976-1978 (Box 47, Folder 12)
      - Coordinator's reports, 1980 Jul - 1982 Jul (Box 47, Folder 13)
      - Associate member application (cluster), n.d. (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence / administrators' files
    - Association of North American Cooperating Agencies of Overseas Women's Christian Colleges: Letters to administrators; members of the Association; nominees to support group, 1974 Aug - 1981 Oct (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - Asian Women's Institute: Letters to "friends"; to Margaret Flory, June Gates, Mira Phailbus, Santush Singha (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - Conferences and consultations
    - Adminstrators' consultation in Seoul, incl. address, "The Future of Women's Christian Higher Education", 1972 May (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Triennial conference of the Presidents of Nine Women's Colleges in Asia; "Directions for the New Triennial", 1978 May-1981 (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Tenth anniversary conference report, 1985 Jan (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Triennial conference: "Together for Justice Through Education and Development" - Indonesia; list of participants, 1988 Jun (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Triennial conference: "Women and Environment in an Age of Technology" - Kobe College, Japan: programme, report, 1991 Sep-Oct (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Programs and projects
    - Peace Education Programm: Report by Traveling Peace Team, 1983 Sep-Oct (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Colleges and centers in Asia
    - List of college presidents, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Tokyo Women's Christian University: Presidents' annual reports, 1979-1982 (Box 48, Folder 24-25)
    - Ewha Womans University: newsletters, report on activities, 1976-1988 (Box 48, Folder 26)
    - Beirut College for Women: establishment of Arab Women's Institute: proposal to Ford Foundation, preliminary report on activities, newsletters - "Al-raida", 1973 Jun - 1978 Aug (Box 48, Folder 27)
    - Kinnaird College: Pakistan Women's Institute - newsletters, report on college, 1982-1992 (Box 48, Folder 28)
  - Publications and promotional material
    - Asian Woman, 1976 Sep-1993 May (Box 48, Folder 29-32)
    - Photographs from AWI events in Korea, Japan, Singapore and India, 1978-1979 (Box 48, Folder 34-36)
  - Collected material
    - Published and typescript articles, 1975-1982 (Box 48, Folder 33)